

11 F, 20, Pangyoyeok-ro 241 beon-gil, Bundang-gu, Seongnam-si, Gyeonggi-do, 13494, Korea □ (+82) 10-4564-4668 | Sh951011@gmail.com | Sooftware.github.io | Sooftware | Soo-hwan

"Who likes to play with codes"

About Me.

Current AI Research Engineer at Kakao Brain. I majored in Electronic & Communication Engineering and minored in Data Science at university. My research interests include technologies for human-machine interaction, such as automatic speech recognition, speech synthesis, and natural language processing. I enjoy software development and sometimes like to write my knowledge or thoughts. I want to be helpful to others through open source. You can check my github page (http://github.com/sooftware) to see what I am currently up to.

Education

AI RESEARCH ENGINEER

Kwangwoon University

Seoul, South Korea

MAJOR IN ELECTRONIC & COMMUNICATION ENGINEERING / MINOR IN DATA SCIENCE Mar. 2014 - Feb. 2021 (Expected)

- Major GPA: 3.90 / 4.5 / Total GPA: 3.69 / 4.5
- Major Courses: Capstone Design I-II, AI & Speech Signal Processing, Software Design, Machine Learning, Computer Architecture, Operating System, Data Structure & Algorithm, Data Mining, Network Programming, IoT System Design, Big Data Language, Big Data Processing & Application, Database, Digital Signal Processing, Statistical application, Object-Oriented Programming, Object-Oriented Programming Practice, Open-Source Software, System Programming, C programming, Mobile Programming, Data Communication, Computer Network, Basic Electronic Circuit Experiment I-II, Electronic Circuit Experiment I-II, Electronic Circuit Theory I-II, Digital Logic, Physics Electronic Technology, Engineering Math I-II, Probability and Irregular Signaling Theory, Probability and Statistics

Professional Experience

Kakao Brain

Nov. 2020 - Present

- Research & Develop Speech and Natural Language Processing fields
- · Develop Natural Language Processing toolkit used to conduct various NLP tasks (e.g. ASR, NMT, TTS, ..., etc.)

Kakao Brain

INTERNSHIP • Research & Develop English, Korean and Chinese Automatic Speech Recognition models

• Development of Multilingual Speech Synthesis Model with Support for 10 Languages

Spoken Language Lab (of Sogang Univ.)

Mapo, Seoul

Apr. 2020 - Aug. 2020

Aug. 2020 - Nov. 2020

- Research End-to-End Automatic Speech Recognition Models
- · Research Real-time Automatic Speech Recognition Based on Kaldi Toolkit

Research Interests

Undergraduate Researcher

Speech Speech Recognition, Speech Synthesis, Voice Activity Detection, Speech Enhancement, Speech Separation

Dialogue System, Machine Translation, Language Model, Cross-lingual

Software Software Architecture, Object-Oriented Programming, Data Structure, Algorithm

Skills

Programming Python, Java, C/C++, Shell Script, SQL, Android, Arduino, Assembly, HTML

Deep Learning PyTorch, Tensorflow, Fairseq, Transformers, PyTorchLightning, Wav2letter, Faiss, Hydra **Data Analysis** Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Scikit-learn, BeautifulSoup, Selenium, NLTK

Publication

End-to-End Speech Recognition Models in English, Korean and Chinese, Bachelor's Graduation Thesis

2020 KoSpeech: Open-Source Toolkit for End-to-End Korean Speech Recognition, ELSEVIER, SIMPAC

SOOHWAN KIM · RÉSUMÉ JANUARY 15, 2021

Project Experience

Pororo: A Deep Learning based Multilingual NLP Library

Kakao Brain Sep. 2020 - Present

TEAM MEMBER

- Libraries that focus on performing natural language processing tasks
- Responsible for developing speech projects within Pororo

KoSpeech: Open-Source Toolkit for End-to-End Korean Speech Recognition

AUTHOR

Jan. 2020 - Present

- Modular and extensible end-to-end Korean automatic speech recognition (ASR) toolkit
- Currently, over 100 people are stargazer this project [link]

Deep Learning Model Implementation

AUTHOR

Jan. 2020 - Present

- Speech Recognition: DeepSpeech-2, Listen-Attend-Spell, Speech-Transformer, Joint CTC-Attention, Jasper
- · Speech Synthesis: Tacotron2, Multilingual-Tacotron2
- Natural Language Processing: RNN-LM, Seq2seq, Transformer

Extracurricular Activity

NLP Paper Reading

Kakao Brain

GROUP MEMBER Sep. 2020 - Present

- Kakao Brain Natural Language Processing Team's weekly paper reading study
- Reading a paper and summarizing its contents [link]

Technical Blog Naver Blog

Writer

- Technical posting of deep learning, programming, signal processing, paper review etc.
 Having more than 100 subscribers and an average of 200 visitors a day [link]
- **Speech Recognition Study Group**

Kwangwoon University

Jan. 2020 - Mar. 2020

Aug. 2018 - Present

- GROUP MEMBER

 Study speech signal processing (Spectrogram, Mel-Scale, MFCC etc..)
- Reading a paper of speech recognition and recording its contents [link]

Teaching Experience

Samsung Al Expert Course - Speech Recognition

Spoken Language Lab

TEACHING ASSISTANT

Jul. 2020 - Aug. 2020

• Conducted Teaching Assistant role in the Speech Recognition session

Object-Oriented Programming Practice

Kwangwoon University

TEACHING ASSISTANT

Mar. 2020 - Jun. 2020

- · Covered basic JAVA programming, Ran laboratories and had office hours every week.
- Answered students' questions in person and marked assignments

Awards & Honors

AWARDS

2020.11 1st Place	, People's Choice Award	, Kwangwoon	Engineering	Festival	(President's Award)
--------------------------	-------------------------	-------------	-------------	----------	---------------------

2019.10 Finalist (12th Place), Naver A.I Hackathon - Speech

2019.09 Finalist, Kwangwoon University software start-up idea contest - Fall

2019.04 People's Choice Award, Kwangwoon University software start-up idea contest - Spring

2018.08 Best Award, Samsung Multi-Campus in Java-based Algorithm for SW Development

Honors

- 2020.03 School Representative, 5G-based ICT Convergence Service Idea Contest
- 2020.03 Excellent Scholarship, Samsong Scholarship
- 2019.03 Excellent Scholarship, Samsong Scholarship
- 2019.03 Academic Excellent Scholarship, Kwangwoon University
- 2018.09 Academic Excellent Scholarship, Kwangwoon University
- 2018.03 Academic Excellent Scholarship, Kwangwoon University